JUSTIN HART

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



847.340.4789



in /justinhart90



/justinhart90



justinhart90@gmail



justin-hart.web.app



Denver, CO

TECHNICAL TOOLS

JavaScript (ES6+) **TypeScript**

Back End

Node.is

Express.is

MongoDB

PostgreSQL

GraphQL

Knex.js

ASP.NET Core

Front End

React.is

Redux

AngularJS

HTML5

CSS3

SASS

Bootstrap

iQuery

D3.js

XML

Testing

Mocha / Chai Jasmine Jest

DevOps

Git / GitHub

AWS Lamda, S3

Webpack

Gulp

Ionic

NPM / Yarn

SUMMARY

Innovative software engineer with five years of Project Management experience and three years of experience in the full software development lifecycle - from concept through delivery - including continuous maintenance and support.

Experience building and supporting 20+ mobile and desktop applications, including advanced API integrations, with Fortune 500 companies.

Known for excellent troubleshooting skills - able to analyze code and engineer well-researched, cost-effective and responsive solutions.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Developer, Rocky Mountain Devs Remote - 2020-Present

Utilize a diverse blend of business and software engineering experience to find creative solutions to client's problems.

Lead Solutions Engineer, JourneyApps Denver, CO — 2019-2020

Designed and implemented software solutions, including collecting requirements, engineering estimations, data modeling, UI/UX design, and the implementation of advanced external integrations including customer ERP/Financial systems.

Managed an international development team, including weekly individual meetings with each member to coach, train, mentor and ensure their personal, professional and technical advancement.

Organized and led external client meetings and workshops; collaborated with executives, account managers and other technical stakeholders to continuously align technical capabilities with client needs.

Software Solutions Engineer, JourneyApps Denver, CO - 2017-2018

Utilized a cloud-based app platform that included writing business logic in JavaScript, implementing extensible data models and building server-side integrations and data processing tasks using Node.js and AWS Lambda.

Maintained a strong focus to deliver core value early, aiming to have a usable solution ready within 4 to 8 weeks.

Project Manager, Ricoh USA

Remote - 2012-2017

Configured and managed the implementation of a Professional Services Automation (PSA) tool that increased operational efficiency by automating processes, discovering new business intelligence through internal reporting, and reducing how many employees are needed for a project. Earned the RICOH Way Award in 2016 for achievements in innovation and automation.

EDUCATION

Galvanize Inc - Denver, Platte

2017

2013

Full Stack Web Development (24-week immersive program)

Project Management Institute — Denver, CO

PMI Certified Associate in Project Management

University of Colorado at Boulder

2008-2012

Bachelor of Science (BS), Business Administration, Finance